# **Jack Fischer**

# Full-Stack Web Developer

Remote/Miami Beach, FL | <u>letsbuild@jackbuildstech.com</u> <u>https://jackbuildstech.com</u> | <u>https://github.com/sunspla-sh</u>

# **Summary**

I do tech. Visit my personal site <a href="https://jackbuildstech.com">https://jackbuildstech.com</a> for a summary of my projects and experience. Everything listed on this resume can also be found on my personal site, which has a better user experience and user interface than this piece of paper... you can also see my video resume here: <a href="https://youtu.be/Di2BlgfSh\_E">https://youtu.be/Di2BlgfSh\_E</a>

# **Experience**

## Full Stack Web Development Instructor

March 2022 - January 2023

Ironhack (https://ironhack.com)

- My former students collectively earn roughly \$800,000-1,000,000 in annual income as junior web developers (or similar tech jobs) with an average salary in the \$50,000-60,000 range (representing a 50-100% increase in annual income for most of them, because they primarily came from a hospitality or retail service background)
- Taught 4 cohorts of students to use modern, full stack web development technologies such as the following: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Mobile-first (Responsive) Design, Express, Handlebars, Databases (MongoDB), ODMs (Mongoose), Single-page Applications (React), Version Control (Git and Github), Unit Testing (Jest), Deployment, etc.

# Failed Startups - Multiple Attempts

September 2021 - February 2022

Failed Startups

- Rejected from YCombinator with first moonshot idea the idea was capital-intensive and we had no clear path forward (and no cash), so my co-founders returned to their jobs
- Continued on solo with second idea scuba diving booking software-as-a-service - I tried to be smarter this time and pre-sell based on UX/UI wireframes before building it, but failed to find product-market fit (basically I ran out of savings)

#### **Gap Year - Spanish Language**

**August 2020 - August 2021** 

Playa Del Carmen (Mexico), Austin TX, Denver CO, Salt Lake City UT

• Studied Spanish in Mexico to a tested level of CEFR Level B1 - Intermediate (Level B1 is high enough to gain entrance to some

- universities in Spain such as <u>Universidad Complutense Madrid</u> while others require B2)
- Spanish exam credential can be independently verified at the following website (<a href="https://siele.org/en/comprobar-certificado">https://siele.org/en/comprobar-certificado</a>) using my credential ID: <a href="https://siele.org/en/comprobar-certificado">li3knEHpdbkjrFuagvJ7RA==</a>
- Learned to scuba dive and earned both Open Water and Advanced Open Water Diver certifications through PADI (Professional Association of Diving Instructors)
- Tried living in various US cities (1-2 months per city) to determine if I
  wanted to settle in any of them long-term

#### Front-End Web Developer (Contractor)

April 2019 - July 2020

Carnival Cruise Line (<a href="https://carnival.com">https://carnival.com</a>)

- Built various front end sections of the carnival.com site including updated versions of the checkout review page within the booking engine, mobile menu, modals, banners, sliders etc
- A/B tested code and toggled features using Optimizely to verify that newly coded sections of the site increased overall customer conversions/revenue
- Hired and managed 4 subcontractors doing front end web development, ux/ui design, and data analytics, who were billed under me and worked alongside me at Carnival

# **Projects (Practice & Personal)**

## 1) JobAppTrack

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/simple-job-app-tracker-react)

Technologies Used:

Docker, Vite, React, CSS, JavaScript, Prisma, SQLite, Node.js, Express, Nodemailer, Handlebars, Open Graph Protocol, CRXJS, pnpm, TurboRepo, Socket.io (Websockets), Fly.io

#### 2) GitBoxDraw

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/github-commit-text-generator)

Technologies Used:

Vite, Sass, HTML, JavaScript, Open Graph Protocol, Node.js, Rollup, JavaScript Obfuscator (Rollup Plugin), npm, DigitalOcean

#### 3) IPomg

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/ipomg-static)

Technologies Used:

Vite, TailwindCSS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MaxMind GeoLite2 DB, Node.js, Express, npm, DigitalOcean

### 4) CommandLineCartography

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/command-line-cartography-practice)

Technologies Used:

D3, GeoJSON, TopoJSON, pnpm, U.S. Census Bureau Data

#### 5) S Tier Web Dev (Tutorials - YouTube Channel)

(https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgF6apjFR90209B4006e8qpNV7qUC-bUD)

Technologies Used:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Various Recording and Editing Software (Kdenlive, OBS, GIMP, YoutubeStudio, Podia)

#### 6) NFL Team Data Scraper

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/nfl-team-data-scraper)

Technologies Used:

Puppeteer, Node.js, npm

# **Tech Skills and Theory**

#### Front-End Web Development

JavaScript, Single-page Applications (React), GraphQL, HTML, CSS, SASS, TailwindCSS, Mobile-first (Responsive) Design, D3, Vite, Chrome Extensions (CRXJS), npm, pnpm, Open Graph Protocol, Websockets (Socket.io)

## **Back-End Web Development**

Node.js, Web Application Frameworks and APIs (Express), Databases (MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite), ODMs and ORMs (Mongoose, Sequelize, Prisma), GraphQL, Unit Testing (Jest), Puppeteer, Nodemailer, Email Templating (Handlebars), Websockets (Socket.io), MVC architecture, npm, pnpm, GeoJSON, TopoJSON, JSON, XML

## **DevOps and Tooling**

Version Control (Git), CI/CD (TravisCI), Cloud Infrastructure (DigitalOcean, AWS, Fly.io, Heroku), Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Monorepos, Bundlers and Build Systems (TurboRepo, Rollup), Postman

## **Other Skills**

#### Languages:

English (Native),

Spanish (CEFR - Level B1 - SIELE - <u>Credential ID li3knEHpdbkjrFuagvJ7RA==</u>), Russian (CEFR - Level A1)

#### Video and Image Editing:

Kdenlive (Video Editing), OBS (Video recording and livestreaming) GIMP (Image Editing)

#### Education

#### Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp - Ironhack

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

10-week intensive (400+ hour) web development boot camp which complimented my existing computer science skills from some of my university classes

## **Study Abroad** - Moscow State University

May 2016 - Aug 2016

I like learning languages. I studied Russian language and culture during a summer abroad and visited various cities in Russia.

#### **Liberal Studies, B.A.** - Iowa State University

Aug 2014 - Jun 2018

I should have been focused on building technical skills instead of "following my passion" and taking a bunch of random liberal arts classes. Fortunately, younger me decided to fill some elective classes with computer science subjects, which led to my current career.